KUNAL KOLHE





SUMMARY

Software Engineer having strong analytical ability, problem-solving skill, proficient in Python, C++ with over 3.0 years of industry experience in software development, analytics, data science with extensive experience in analysis, manipulating, processing, insights and machine learning techniques to meet business needs. Highly motivated individual, team player, quick learner who aims to contribute towards consistent organizational growth.

KEY SKILLS

Programing Languages/Tools – Python, C/C++, OOPS, HTML

Machine/ Deep Learning Libraires - Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Scipy, TensorFlow, Keras, Selenium, Pycaret

Data Visualizations – Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau

Natural Language Processing Libraires – NLTK, TextBlob, Gensim, FastText

Database Technologies - MySQL

Web Frameworks/ Cloud Services - Flask, Heroku, AWS, API

IDE/ Platforms - Jupyter Notebook/ lab, Visual Studio, PyCharm, Spider, Google Colab, Eclipse, Windows, Linux

Issue Tracking/ Version Control System - Jira, Git, SVN

WORK EXPERIENCE

63 Moons Technologies – Andheri, Mumbai (HQ)

Software Engineer (ML) - (May 2021 – Oct. 2021)

- ODIN is a trading platform for end user to trades in equity, derivatives, mutual funds, IPOs, currencies, commodities from single screen in BSE, NSE, MCX and NCDEX.
- Developed solutions for stock data analysis, scripts price predictions under organizational policies for product enhancement using python, machine learning and deep learning.
- Automated Jira process, work-logs, validations using selenium and minimized review efforts by 0.5 hours.
- Demonstrated stock data extraction for NSE, BSE markets by web-scraping and provided quality datasets to teams.

Innodatatics Inc. – Hydrabad (HQ: USA)

Data Science Engineer - (Jan. 2021 – Apr. 2021)

- Analyzed large and imbalanced data consisting more than 120K records with 24 features using ML techniques to provide data insights and strategic directions.
- Built predictive and optimal decision models using machine learning algorithms for various business study cases with features engineering and evaluation methods in details.
- Supported in ML/AI and NLP application deployments on web-based frameworks heroku, streamlit and flask.
- Worked on NLP module with text mining techniques, extraction, cleaning, pattern identifications, categorizations and entity recognitions.

KPIT Technologies - Rajiv Gandhi Infotech Park, Pune (HQ)

Software Engineer - (Jan. 2019 – Dec. 2020)

- Collected data insights from client vehicle sensors raw data with more than 94K records, worked on clustering algorithms and generated tableau dashboards.
- Closely interacted with analyst, internal research teams to translate business requirements into technical solutions with review process time reduction by 0.75 hours.
- Developed and integrated UI components with HMI framework in Head Up Display, infotainment system using Python, C++ 11 with object-oriented approach.
- Collaborated on all the stages of software development life cycle from requirements gathering to production releases.

Software Trainee - (Oct. 2018 – Dec. 2018)

- Defined automations for test case creation, client inputs online checker using python and increased team productivity by 35%.
- Managed highest levels of development practices including unit test, technical and functional design, issues identification and resolution.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Recognized as Crown Developer out of 180 employees. Gold Medalist at University Carrom Championship.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate Program in Data Science using ML with Python (IBM) Data Science Certification (ExcelR)

PARTICIPATIONS

Technical DevFest event (GDG, India)

Microsoft Al classroom series program (Microsoft, India)

AWS SA foundation program (Sunbeam, Pune)

Machine learning with explainable AI (TMLC Academy)

EDUCATION

CDAC Kharghar – New Mumbai (2018)

Post graduate degree in Computer Science (PG-DAC)

BATU University – BATU, Lonere, Raigad (2017)
Bachelor degree in Electrical Engineering (B-Tech)

PROJECTS

63 Moons Technologies (Domain: Finance/ Investment)

Title: Stock Exchange Analysis in ODIN (May 2021 – Oct. 2021)

- Contributed in NSE scripts stock price predictions using machine learning, deep learning mechanism by implementing LSTM model with 94% of average accuracy and less than 1% RMSE.
- Researched top gainer and looser stocks companies with NSE indices NITFY 50, NIFTY MIDCAP 50 in banking, pharma, IT sectors on daily, weekly, monthly basis and shared outputs on Amazon S3 bucket.
- Handled stock brokers CRs on prior, actively involved in scrum activities, code reviews and followed SDLC with product policies.

Innodatatics Inc. (Domain: Banking/ Healthcare)

Title: Hospital Insurance Fraud Claims Detection (Feb. 2021 – Apr. 2021)

- Performed strong EDA, features engineering, data insights using python, tableau and provided results to stakeholders.
- Used Random Forest Classifier, data balancing techniques for imbalanced nature, stratified K-Folds as cross validation and achieved model accuracy of 92% with F1-score 89%.
- Designed UI components with HTML, Bootstrap, CSS and integrated ML applications using PaaS on cloud.

Title: Text Analytics - Drugs Effectiveness with Side Effects (Jan. 2021 – Feb. 2021)

- Collected 100K online customer reviews from drug website by developing web scrappers using selenium.
- Performed text extraction, processing, cleaning and implemented FastText for foreign languages detection.
- Calculated drug effectiveness based on polarities, user reviews, side effects and shared overall analytical reports, model interpretations to business lead with deployed ML solution on cloud using streamlit and heroku.

KPIT Technologies (Domain: Automotive)

Title: HUD Cluster Data Analysis and Development - (Feb. 2020 – Dec. 2020)

- Created EDA scripts to analyzed in-vehicle sensors data, used K-Means clustering algorithm to collect similar sensors datapoints and formed silhouette mean score 0.87.
- Modified data scraping pipeline by python automation, analyzed and cleaned data, shared quality datasets with teams.
- Refined previous SVN pipeline by adding detailed checkpoints in review process for quality code reviews and zero bug delivery.

Title: Text Based Application Analytics - (Apr. 2019 – Jan. 2020)

- Worked on documents parsing and text analytics of application portal with internal research project teams.
- Updated existing architecture with NLTK library by capturing text fields and executed text mining tasks, cleaning, pattern matching, text extraction with specified fields.
- Automated the application analysis reports to analyst and management team.

Title: Design in-Vehicle Infotainment System - (Oct. 2018 – Mar. 2019)

- A POC based project to integrate the framework with application for in-vehicle infotainment system using python, C++11/14.
- Computed various module screens using Qt-QML, compiled middleware with stubbing and maintained application work flow.